comic-con.org 2018-01-04

# Privacy Policy | Comic-Con International: San Diego

For purposes of this Privacy Policy, the terms "we," "us," "our" and "Comic-Con International" refer to San Diego Comic Convention and all other affiliates of San Diego Comic Convention. "You" and "your" refers to you, as a user of our website. The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to disclose to you what information we may collect, how we may collect it, with whom we may share it, and certain other matters related to such information, including the choices you have regarding our collection of information and our use and disclosure to other parties of information we may have collected from you.

**Comic-Con International is committed to protecting your privacy.**

By using our website at http://www.comic-con.org/ or other Comic-Con owned websites ("Site") and accepting our Website Terms of Service, you consent to our collection and use of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to these terms, please do not access or use this Site. This Privacy Policy applies to individuals and we reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy, along with related procedures, at any time.

We use the information we collect about you to facilitate commercial transactions and to provide you with a more personalized experience. We have created this Privacy Policy in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to protecting the privacy of all of our customers and visitors. The following Privacy Policy discloses the information-gathering and dissemination practices and policies of Comic-Con International.

Except as otherwise discussed in this Privacy Policy, this document only addresses the use and disclosure of information we collect from you online. For some services, we collect and transfer personal information to third-parties assisting with online registration or other event or website issues. Please read the following to learn more about our data collection policies and practices.

  1. Types of Information that may be collected
  2. How is information collected?
  3. How we use the information we collect
  4. With whom the information may be shared?
  5. What choices do I have about Comic-Con International collecting, using, and sharing my information?
  6. What security precautions are in place to protect against the loss, misuse, or alteration of your information?
  7. Links to other Websites
  8. A special note for parents concerning privacy
  9. Limitation of Liability
  10. Notification of changes and acceptance of the Privacy Policy
  11. Correcting and updating personal information
  12. Whom do I contact with questions or concerns about this privacy policy?

**Types of information that may be collected**

The personally identifiable information we collect is used to facilitate delivery of information regarding registration, important updates, and/or Comic- Con International newsletter/magazine mailings to our customers. In the process of providing these services, we require our customers to provide certain personally identifiable information. Specific details may include, but is not limited to the following and may be subject to change.

The personally identifiable information that may be collected from our customers in completion of a Member ID registration form, purchase of a badge, email correspondence, posting a review or comment on our Site or the entry of a contest or sweepstakes includes customer's first name, last name, age, gender, home city and zip code, phone number, member type, email address and credit card number.

We may also automatically collect your internet protocol and referring website addresses, browser type, and domain name. This information helps facilitate your online experience on our Site. In addition, we may use cookies to track usage patterns on our Site and to control the display of certain functionalities. You can turn off cookies, but that may affect your online experience. Please see below for more detail on cookies.

**How is the information collected?**

We may collect information from you in several different areas on the Site, including but not limited to those described below:

  * **Member ID Registration Form**  
You may be asked first to complete a registration form and provide personally identifiable information; you may also be asked to choose a Member ID and password in order to take advantage of certain features the Site offers, including, but not limited to, Newsletters, Magazines, Contests, Forums or other subscription based services.
  * **Newsletters and Registration Emails**  
We may offer free newsletters/magazines to share information with you about us and/our affiliates, or about our business partners and advertisers and sponsors. You may cancel your free email or postal mail subscription by following the instructions provided on the Site or, in some instances, in the designated area of certain newsletters or emails.
  * **Contests or Sweepstakes**  
We may operate contests and sweepstakes through the Site, which may require registration. Your personally identifiable information may be used to contact you for winner notification, prize delivery confirmation or other related purposes. We may ask your permission to allow us to post publicly some of your information on the Site, such as on a winners page, in the event you win a contest or sweepstakes. Except as required by applicable law, we will not post your information without your permission.
  * **Cookies**  
As with many websites, the Site uses standard technology called "cookies," which are small data files that are transferred to your computer when you allow your browser to accept cookies. Cookies automatically identify your Web browser to the Site whenever you visit the Site, and make using the Site easier for you by saving your passwords, purchases, and preferences. By tracking how and when you use the Site, cookies help us determine which areas are popular and which are not. Many improvements and updates to the Site are based on data obtained from cookies. Accepting cookies allows you, among other things, to personalize your experience on the Site. Cookies may also allow the Site to present to you advertising which may be of interest to you. If you do not want information collected through the use of cookies, you generally can Opt-Out of providing this information by turning the cookies off in your browser; however, some areas of the Site may not provide you with a personalized experience if you have disabled the use of cookies.
  * **IP Addresses and Click-stream Data**  
We may collect IP addresses and/or click-stream data for purposes of system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers and sponsors. An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you access the Internet. Our computers identify your computer by its IP address. When you request Web pages from the Site, our computers log your IP address. Click-stream data is information collected by our computers when you request Web pages from the Site. Click-stream data may include such information as the page served, the time, the source of the request, the type of browser making the request, the preceding page view and other such non-personal information. When analyzed, this data helps us analyze how visitors arrive at the Site, what type of content is most popular, what type of visitors in the aggregate are interested in particular kinds of content and advertising, and the like.

**How we use the information we collect**

We internally use personally identifiable information about our customers to improve our marketing and promotional efforts, to improve our content and product offerings and to customize our Site's content and layout. We also use collected information to evaluate and administer our products and services, fulfill customer requests, respond to any future problems, such as difficulties in navigating our Site or accessing certain features, and to gauge user trends to determine what products and services are most popular with users. We believe these uses allow us to improve our Site and provide better service to our customers.

We may occasionally use a customer's email address and, in rare situations mailing address or phone number, to contact a customer regarding administrative matters or notices.

We may use information in the file we maintain about a customer to resolve disputes and troubleshoot problems.

As in any transaction, when you make purchases on our Site your credit card company will have all relevant information about the name of the vendor, item(s) purchased, date, total cost and other information necessary to process the transaction.

**With whom the information may be shared?**

Information we collect may be accessed by a variety of parties, depending upon the project for which the information was originally collected, the terms of that engagement, and the policies into or out of which the consumer has opted. From time to time, we may send you offers from Comic-Con International, its affiliated properties, and our promotional partners based on the information you have provided us. We may share anonymous, aggregate demographic information and anonymous information obtained from cookies and similar technologies, with our advertisers, sponsors, promotional and business partners, and participating vendors. In addition, we will provide information we collect about you with third party companies involved with online badge registration or hotel room reservations. These third parties are subject to stringent data security and confidentiality requirements. These companies need access to member personal information in order to process on-line badge purchases or hotel room reservation requests.

Some of the third party content displayed on our Site is provided by outside companies. This content may contain cookies and may also contain web beacons. We do not have access to information collected from cookies or web beacons received in connection with third party content. While we use third parties which we believe are reputable to serve some or all of the content placed on our Site, third parties may use information (not including personally identifiable information) about your visits to our Site and other websites to assist in serving their third party content to you. They may also share information with their clients such as date/time of the content shown, the specific content shown, the internet protocol address and other similar information.

**Important Note**

We reserve the right to use or disclose any information without notice or consent for the following purposes: as needed to satisfy any law, regulation or legal request; to conduct investigations of consumer complaints or possible breaches of law; to protect the integrity of our Site and our property; to protect the safety of our visitors or others; to fulfill your requests; or to cooperate in any legal investigation. In addition, in the event Comic-Con International (or substantially all of our assets) is acquired, consumer information would be transferred along with the other business assets as permitted by law. We may also disclose personally identifiable information to non-affiliated third parties as permitted by law.

**What choices do I have about Comic-Con International collecting, using, and sharing my information?**

While we believe the limited disclosure of your information will result in opportunities that may be of interest to you, you have the right to tell us not to give your information to any third party. As noted above, Comic-Con International uses third-party venders for various administrative functions (e.g., Registration) for its events. In order for these venders to be able to provide the necessary services they need to have access to member information.

Given the concerns relating to the transfer of member information, we allow members to control the scope of transfer by providing two types of Opt-Outs for member information. The first Opt-Out allows a member to Opt-Out of having their information transferred to third-parties who are not involved in any administrative or operational aspect of an event. Selecting this Opt-Out still allows Comic-Con International to transfer the information on an as needed basis to venders who are involved in administrative or operational aspects of an event. To select this Opt-Out, login to your Member ID account, select the "Change My Preferences" option, then select the "Non-Critical Transfers" Opt- Out.

The second Opt-Out is for those members who do not want any of the information transferred to any third party. This Opt-Out If you do not want Comic-Con International to share your information with any third party, login to your Member ID account, select the "Change My Preferences" option, and select the "Cancel Member ID" Opt-Out. Please note that by selecting this "Cancel Member ID" option, your Comic-Con membership will be canceled and you will not be able to purchase badges and you will not be able to make hotel reservations through our vender. If you have already purchased a badge for Comic-Con 2012, that badge will be canceled and the purchase price will be refunded if the membership cancelation was requested before the refund deadline. Periodically our website may not allow members to enter "Cancel Member ID" requests due to system maintenance or for other reasons. If this occurs, please try again at a later date.

**What security precautions are in place to protect against the loss, misuse, or alteration of your information?**

We use standard industry practices to safeguard the confidentiality of your personally identifiable information. Although we have implemented systems and procedures intended to secure the data maintained by us, security can never be assured. Please keep in mind that "perfect security" does not exist on the Internet and/or the World Wide Web. Remember, however, that any personal information you post on the internet may be available to anyone.

**Links to other Websites**

You should be aware that when you are on the Site you could be directed to other sites beyond our control. For example, if you "click" on a banner advertisement, the "click" may take you off the Site onto a different website. This includes links from advertisers, sponsors and partners that may use the Site's logo as part of a co-branding agreement. We are not responsible for practices employed by websites linked to or from our Site, nor the information or content contained therein. These other Websites may send their own cookies to you, independently collect data or solicit personal information and may or may not have their own published privacy policies. Please remember that when you use a link to go from our Site to another website, our Privacy Policy is no longer in effect. Your browsing and interaction on any other web site, including websites which have a link to our Site, is subject to that website's own rules and policies. Please read those rules and policies before proceeding or providing any personal information.

**A special note for parents concerning privacy**

None of the information on the Site is intended for users under 13 years of age, and Comic-Con International does not knowingly register any person or accept information from any person under the age of 13.

We do not encourage children to participate in providing us with any personally identifiable information. We ask that children (12 years of age and under) do not submit any personal information to us. If you are a minor under the age of 13 years, you will not be allowed to complete a Member ID Registration form.

We support the guidelines and regulatory requirements provided in the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA): <http://www.ftc.gov/ogc/coppa1.htm>

**Limitation of Liability**

By providing us with any personal information you expressly and unconditionally release and hold harmless Comic-Con International, and its subsidiaries, affiliates, directors, officers, employees and agents from any and all liability for any injuries, loss or damage of any kind arising from or in connection with the use and/or misuse of your collected personal information. In addition, while Comic-Con International takes efforts to ensure the proper and appropriate use of Comic-Con International data provided by Comic-Con International to third party companies, promotional partners or vendors, Comic- Con International is not liable for any injuries, loss or damage of any kind arising from or in connection with the use and/or misuse of your collected personal information by Comic-Con International or the above-mentioned non- Comic-Con International entities.

**Notification of changes and acceptance of the Privacy Policy**

By using this Site, you signify your agreement to the terms of our Privacy Policy. Comic-Con International may change this policy from time to time. If so, any such changes will be posted on this page, so that Comic-Con International may keep its users informed of its information collection practices. Accordingly, we recommend that you consult this page frequently so that you are aware of our latest policy. Your continued use of the Site shall constitute your acceptance of such revised Privacy Policy.

**Correcting and updating personal information**

If your personally identifiable information changes (such as your zip code), or if you no longer desire to access our Site, we will endeavor to provide a way to correct, update or remove the personal data you have provided to us. This can be done by making changes to your Member ID account. Please click here to make any changes to your profile and/or Opt-Out of Comic-Con International.

**Whom do I contact with questions or concerns about this privacy policy**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this Site, or your dealings with this Site, please contact Comic-Con International by sending a letter to:

Attn: Privacy Policy  
Comic-Con International  
PO Box 128458  
San Diego, CA 92112
